<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" 
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://hl7.org/fhir ../../input-cache/schemas-r5/fhir-single.xsd">

    
     <a name="volume1"></a><h3>Purpose</h3>

    <p>The CH RAD-Order Implementation Guide defines the content of a radiolgy order and covers the follwing use cases:
    </p>
   
    <ul>
        <li>Referral for imaging</li>
        <li>Referral for radiological intervention</li>
        <li>Request for second opinion</li>
        <li>Request for remote reporting</li>
        <li>Request for precedent imaging results</li>
    </ul>

    <p>CH RAD-Order is intended for use in directional communication as well as for the use in the SWISS EPR.
    </p>  

    <p>
        <b>Download:</b>
        You can download this Implementation Guide in 
        <a href="https://confluence.hl7.org/display/FHIR/NPM+Package+Specification">NPM format</a> from 
        <a href="package.tgz">here</a>.
    </p>

  <a name="volume1"></a><h3>Foundation</h3>
    
    <p>This Implementation Guide uses FHIR defined resources. For details on HL7 FHIR R4 see <a href="http://hl7.org/fhir/r4">http://hl7.org/fhir/r4</a>.
    </p>
    <p>Because the Implementation Guide relies heavily on the FHIR Resources Questionnaire and QuestionnaireResponse, forms are addressed here as Questionnaires.
    </p>
    
    <p>This Implementation Guide is derived from the Order &amp; Referral by Form (ORF) Implementation Guide  
        <a href="http://build.fhir.org/ig/hl7ch/ch-orf/index.html">CH ORF</a> which relies on HL7 Structured Data Capture Implementation Guide, see
        <a href="http://build.fhir.org/ig/HL7/sdc/">SDC IG</a> and uses the Swiss Core Profiles, see 
        <a href="http://build.fhir.org/ig/hl7ch/ch-core/index.html">CH Core</a>.
    </p>

    <p>Applications claiming for conformance with the CH RAD-Order Implementation Guide shall:
    </p>
        <ul>
            <li>Render (and in case of the Questionnaire filler allow for data entry) all elements of a questionnaire in the user interface
            (e.g. on screen, in print).</li> 
            
            <li>For Clinical Information: Grouping of items and the order of items within shall be adequately reproduced according to the Questionnaire.</li>
        </ul>

    <p> Actors, transcations and security considerations are covered in the corresponding sections of 
        <a href="http://build.fhir.org/ig/hl7ch/ch-orf/index.html">CH ORF</a>.
    </p>

    <a name="volume3"></a><h3>Terminology</h3>

    <p>CH RAD-Order allows coding of the requested imaging service by means of <a href="https://loinc.org/collaboration/rsna/">LOINC/RSNA RADIOL0GY PLAYBOOK</a>.
    </p>
    <p>Systems such as PIS and KIS may not yet support RADIOLGY PLAYBOOK. For this reason, CH RAD-Order allows coding of the relevant dimensions 
    by means of <a href= "https://www.rsna.org/practice-tools/data-tools-and-standards/radlex-radiology-lexicon">RADLEX</a>.
     </p>

    <p>The relevant dimensions are defined by PLAYBOOK such as:
    </p>
    <ul>
        <li>Modality</li>
        <li>Region</li>
        <li>Focus</li>
        <li>Laterlity</li>
        <li>Maneuvre</li>
        <li>Guidance for action (used for interventions)</li>    
    </ul>
  
    <p> Coding of these dimensions is done by <a href= "https://www.rsna.org/practice-tools/data-tools-and-standards/radlex-radiology-lexicon">RADLEX terms</a>.
    </p> 

    <p>Value sets and coding are preliminary and not yet approved by eHealth Suisse.
    </p> 

</div>